Hello and welcome
to the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner course.
My name is Stephane Maarek and I will be your instructor.
So, we are starting in five minutes
but please, try to pay attention to this lecture.
So we are going to prepare for the Cloud Practitioner exam.
The code is CLF-C01.
It is a challenging certification so,
this course is going to be long and interesting
and it is good if you have some basic IT knowledge
but don't worry if you don't come from an IT background,
I will explain everything for you as well.
In this course, we're going to learn a lot.
We will cover over 40 AWS services,
out of the 200 plus that exist in AWS.
If you are a beginner in IT and AWS,
do not worry, you are welcome to this course
and you will learn a lot
but take your time, it's not a race.
You will learn a lot everyday by doing little by little.
Then, this course is a bit special
because I want you to learn also by doing.
It's a key learning technique in this course.
So, this course will mix both theory lectures
and where necessary, hands on
where you can follow along
with me in the course by creating your own AWS account
and reproducing what I do on screen.
So now, we're preparing for a certification.
I want to show you the type
of questions you're going to get.
So this is sample question from the exam
which says, "Which AWS "service would simplify
"the migration of a database to AWS?"
And we'll have four answers,
Storage Gateway, Database Migration Service,
EC2 and Amazon AppStream 2.0.
Now, this course is going to cover most of the services.
For example, the first service we will learn in this course.
The second service, the name is obvious,
it is the answer to the question,
that is the correct answer
and we will cover this service as well.
For EC2, we will learn as well
and it is possible in the course
to have services that will be called distractors.
So, they will not be covered in the course
because there are over 200 services in AWS
but they will appear at the exam as a wrong answer.
So in this course,
I wanna focus on the service that I know are core to AWS
and they will come up at the exam
but I will not focus on explaining to you
the distractors because that would make
too much information into your head.
If you're interested into checking out
the sample questions for the exam,
you can use this link.
So now that we know a little bit more about the exam,
I want to introduce myself.
My name is Stephane Maarek
and I will be your instructor.
I am nine times certified on AWS out
of 12 certification and that's so far.
I'll be going for the 12 certifications
hopefully before the end of the year 2020.
I've worked with AWS for many years.
I've built websites, application and streaming platforms
and I've been teaching about AWS for a long time.
I teach about many AWS certifications,
CloudFormation, Lambda, EC2 and other courses.
As you can see, over 300,000 students
have learned alongside with me
and I have received over 100,000 reviews.
I think you are in good hands.
So, if you want to connect with me,
you can follow me on LinkedIn,
you can follow me on Medium,
Twitter as well as GitHub.
So welcome to AWS.
You are going to get certified
and you are going to get the first certification in AWS,
called the Foundational Certification
for AWS Cloud Practitioner.
This is a great first choice
but this is pretty high level.
If you want to deepen your knowledge
and get more technical about AWS then after this course,
I would recommend you tackle the Associate Certifications.
Then if you're really an aficionado of AWS
and want to learn more and more and more,
the Specialty exam
and the Professional exams are really difficult
and will test your in depth knowledge.
In this course,
we're just going
to prepare for the foundational knowledge necessary
to pass with flying colors,
the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner examination.
Finally, I said we're going to practice in this course.
So you may have a question
which is how much will this course cost me?
So this is how much it cost me at the end of this course,
$12 and 70 cents but I wanna tell you right away
that most of the services we'll use in this course,
will be within the AWS Free Tier.
So there is a chance for you to have a cost of zero.
Now, if I use a service in this course
that will cost you money,
I will mention it and I will leave you the option
to not do the hands on with me and just watch me do.
For example, the most expensive item
in here is the registrar
because I've purchased a domain name.
So, new URL, for example stephaneccp.com.
You can read more about the Free Tier at this URL.
If you're unsure about,
if something is going to cost you money
or not or you can just come back
to this slide and then see,
based on the service we're watching
if it's going to cost you anything or not.
As I mentioned,
most of the services we'll be using
will be within the Free Tier.
So don't worry there,
I'll be guiding you along the way.
I am super happy that you're here
with me in this course
and I wish you a happy learning.