So let's go ahead
and create our first AWS account.
So in this instance,
we're going to be leveraging the free tier on AWS.
That means that for most of the hands-on labs,
we're going to try to not spend any money.
And I will tell you if there's a risk
of you spending money,
but most of the things that
we'll do in this course will be free, okay?
So first you have to enter
your email address, your password
and choose an account name.
So for me, it will be Stephane-AWS.
Next, you have to say that
we're going to use AWS for personal,
because we're just going to do a training.
Then you give your full name,
your phone number,
your address and so on.
As well as your postal code.
Next, you need to enter your credit card details
and as you can see here,
there's a secure verification that happens.
That means that even though you're not charged
for whenever you're using the free tier,
they will temporarily hold on US dollar or Euro
in your currency as a pending transaction
for three to five days
to verify your identity.
So this is something they will hold
and reimburse after three to five days.
So if you enter your credit card here
and see a charge,
don't freak out.
It is just an authorization.
Next, AWS will confirm your identity
by asking you for a phone number
and send you a verification code.
And finally, after verifying your accounts,
you have to choose a support plan.
And it will go with basic support
because it's free
and you don't need any kind of support
because you're learning AWS right now.
So let's complete the signup.
And we are now signed up with AWS,
so we'll click on "go to the management console."
And here, you have the possibility
to enter your root user email,
so the email you used to subscribe with.
And then, finally, enter your password
and you're now logged in into the AWS console.
Congratulations, we are almost ready
to get started with this course.