Hi and welcome.
My name is Stephane Maarek and I will be your instructor for this course.
So I'm delighted to have you here.
And I really hope that you'll enjoy this course and go all the way through with it.
So this is just a two minutes introduction so we can get to know me and then we'll get started with
the content itself.
So I am French and so if you hear a small accent this is where it comes from.
From the sweet country of France.
But I've also lived in the United States.
I've lived in Australia and in Portugal and my expertise is going to be around AWS certifications, Apache
Kafka, data engineering and DevOps.
Why.
Well because in my career I've had the chance to go through jobs many of them such as data analyst big
data engineer, developer and more recently solutions architects and obviously well today I'm a teacher.
I love to teach.
This is my passion and I want to help you achieve any goal you may have through online learning.
So before we get started with this course there's two ways you can connect with me.
The first one is on LinkedIn.
And the second one is on Instagram.
So for LinkedIn, this is where we'll share more professional updates.
I will give you updates around new courses and so on.
And this is where I congratulate my students.
If for example you finished of course and have a certificate or you passed a certification then this is
where I would love to hear about it and congratulate you.
And the second project is Instagram and Instagram is a big project of mine because I love to travel
the world and I've decided as I travel the world to meet students and so I've already met students.
And every time I meet the students get coffee I will write about it.
Talk about your achievements.
Talk about your goals or desires.
How the course helped you and write a small blog about it.
So if you want to get the chance to meet me or if you want to read about the future students that I
meet.
Just follow me on Instagram.
And this is where you'll get a bit more personal behind the scenes updates.
Finally just before we get started with this course I want you to set a goal by setting a goal you will
have a much higher chance of finishing this course and learning a lot.
So maybe you want to say OK I want to take this course and finish it in three weeks then write it down
make a plan for it and stick with it.
This is how you learn.
And this is how you'll make the most out of this course.
So that's it for me.
I hope you will enjoy this course and I will see you in the next lecture.
Happy learning.